bplans.co.uk 2016-05-13

# Privacy Policy & Legal Information - Palo Alto Software UK

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practises for paloalto.com, which is owned and operated by Palo Alto Software, Ltd.

_**Personal Information**_

At Palo Alto Software Limited, we are committed to protecting your privacy. Palo Alto Software, Ltd. collects personal information about our users only during the secure order process and the registration for our business planning newsletter, or if you request other information sent to you. We collect name, email address, shipping address, credit card company, credit card number, expiration date, and credit card billing address. This is all kept confidential.

_**Data Protection Act**_  
Palo Alto Software, Ltd. complies fully with the Data Protection Act 1998 and all applicable data protection and privacy legislation. Palo Alto Software will only process personal data in accordance with the applicable rules and this privacy policy. All personal data will be controlled by Palo Alto Software, Ltd.

If you require further information on your rights under the Data Protection Act please contact the Data Protection Commissioner by visiting [www.ico.gov.uk/](http://www.ico.gov.uk/)

Palo Alto Software, Ltd. respects your right to privacy. We have a strict policy of not selling our customers' email addresses and are completely anti-Spam. Our online store is completely secure and VeriSign has authenticated us as a secure site.

_**Affiliates**_  
Palo Alto Software, Ltd. works with a number of third party websites through affiliate agreements and website co-brands. If you access our site through a co-branded site that features both the Palo Alto Software logo and third party website you are on a co-branded page. Palo Alto Software hosts these co-branded sites, and at that time you are subject to our privacy policy. No personally identifiable customer information is ever shared with these third party sites that you came from to access our co-branded sites. We have 30 co-branded sites, including partnerships with Yahoo, the Wall Street Journal, and Intuit. What you've done on their sites prior to accessing the co-branded site falls under their privacy policy, which we encourage you to review. Once you reach the co-branded site that includes our logo, you are now within our privacy guidelines.

The "Send Page to A Friend" feature collects your email address temporarily, only to send your email correctly.

_**Use of Third Party Information**_  
Palo Alto Software will not disclose to any third party any information or data submitted by Users of this website, without the User's prior permission, unless Palo Alto Software has a good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; or (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Palo Alto Software.

You will be notified of any significant privacy statement updates or if we change the way we collect or use personally identifiable information through email, then wait for your consent. We have measures in place to protect your personally identifiable information. Our employees are made aware of these measures when they start working at Palo Alto Software, Ltd. Any time there is a change in security measures, all employees are notified of the change. We are using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption for your credit card transactions, and we are authorized by VeriSign. We do share your credit card information with a third party only for verification purposes. All customer information available to internal employees is only accessible on our internal company network.

The data we collect is used in the aggregate to give us demographic information about the entire Palo Alto Software, Ltd. audience in order to improve our products and services. The information you provide name, address, etc. allows us to keep you informed about upgrades, products and services of Palo Alto Software, Ltd., its affiliates and other third parties that we believe may be of interest to you. If you are a registered user of one of our products, we will only send information regarding your product or any assistance you require. We do not send our business planning newsletter automatically: you will only receive it if you specifically register for it. We only share aggregate information (i.e. number of users, referral URLs, etc.) not individual data with our advertisers to help them better understand our services and to monitor the reach of  
their advertising.

_**Communications**_  
We communicate with our users only if you buy a product, sign up for our planning newsletter, or sign up for our free membership to use one of our planning tools. In each case, you will receive our planning newsletter. If you buy a product, you will receive a confirmation email, and have the choice if you'd like to receive further product offer emails. If you sign up for our free membership, you will receive a login information email, and future product offer emails.

Users have the opportunity to opt-out from receiving these emails by directly replying to the email stating that they wish to opt-out, or by [emailing us](http://www.paloalto.com/uk/contact_us/general_inquiries/) or calling 44 (0) 845 351 9924 and letting us know that you wish to opt-out of our emails.

_**Information Security**_  
Palo Alto Software, Ltd. uses reasonable precautions to keep the personal information disclosed to us secure. However, we are not responsible for any breach of security or for any actions of any third parties which receive the information. In the event of unauthorized use of your credit card, Palo Alto Software will cover your liability up to 50 provided that the unauthorized use of your credit card resulted through no fault of your own from purchases made at Palo Alto Software while using the secure server. Please note: This guarantee only applies to purchases made using our secure server. You must notify your credit card provider of any unauthorized use. Most banks either cover all the charges that result from the unauthorized use or may limit your liability to just £50.

_**Safe Harbour**_  
Palo Alto Software, Ltd. may also transfer personal data to other countries. These may be outside the European Economic Area and may not have adequate laws that protect the rights and freedoms of data subjects in relation to the processing of personal data. Where this is done, Palo Alto Software, Ltd. shall take reasonable steps to enter into agreements that protect the information transferred and will only transfer data to companies in the United States who have registered for "Safe Harbour" with the Federal Trade Commission. By supplying personal data to Palo Alto Software, Ltd. you consent to any such transfer.

Palo Alto Software, Ltd. also links to a wide variety of other sites. We are not responsible for their privacy policies or how they treat information about their users, however, we do encourage you to review their privacy policies. We do not provide these sites with your information.

_**Cookie Policy**_  
Palo Alto Software uses Cookies on this website to improve the service we offer you.

_**What are Cookies?**_

Cookies are small text files that are used on websites for a number of different reasons including improving the browsing experience and to remember preferences. When a visitor first visits a website a cookie can be set locally on the user’s computer or mobile device. When that visitor returns the cookies can be recognised which can then be used to help improve the browsing experience.

There are 4 main types of cookie as described by the [ICC UK](http://www.international-chamber.co.uk/):

  * Strictly Necessary
  * Performance
  * Functionality & Profile
  * Targeting

1\. Strictly Necessary  
These cookies are essential, as they enable you to move around a website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas. Without these cookies, services you've asked for (such as access to secure areas) can't be provided. These cookies don't gather information about you that could be used for marketing or remembering where you've been on the internet.

2\. Performance  
These cookies collect information about how you use a website, for example which pages you go to most often and if you get any error messages from certain pages. These cookies don't gather information that identifies you. We  also utilise other cookies to analyse how our visitors use our websites and to monitor website performance. All information these cookies collect is anonymous and is only used to improve how a website works.

3\. Functionality  
These cookies allow a website to remember preferences you make (such as your user name or geographic location) and tailor the website to provide enhanced features and content for you. For instance, they remember your log-in details and allow you to watch videos.  They also ensure the onsite marketing and experience is relevant to you.

4\. Profile and Targeting.  
These cookies gather information about your browsing habits. They remember that you've visited a website and share this information with other organisations such as advertisers. They do this in order to provide you with ads that are more relevant to you and your interests.

_**What do they do?**_  
Cookies can have a number of different applications (as described above). The primary use is to improve the browsing experience on Palo Alto Software sites. They can also be used by Palo Alto Software to better understand how our website is performing , to determine which adverts to serve and to remember your username so we can personalise the experience for you when you return.

_**How do I accept the cookies?**_  
By continuing to browse on our website, you agree to accept our use of cookies.

_**Setting cookie preferences**_  
You can control how cookies are placed on your device from within your own web browser. If you don’t want to receive cookies, you can modify your browser setting so that it notifies you when cookies are sent to it or you can refuse cookies altogether. You can also delete cookies that have already been set.

_**Issues with opting out**_  
Please remember that if you do choose to disable cookies, you may find that certain parts of the Palo Alto Software website will not work properly.

_**Where can I get more information?**_

_**Managing Information**_  
If you would like to modify, update or delete information that is collected through ordering, or registration please email us or call 44 (0) 845 351 9924.

_**Legal Disclaimer**_  
We may disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process served on our website.

You may provide us with your feedback, ask us questions about this policy, view the information collected from you to date, or obtain a printed copy of our policy statement and/or the name of the individual in charge of our privacy policy by writing to us at::

Data Protection Administration  
Palo Alto Software Ltd  
Dalton House  
60 Windsor Avenue  
London SW19 2RR  
United Kingdom

Please be sure to include your mailing address if you would like us to send you any written materials.

If at any time you wish your personal data to be deleted from our files, please contact us in writing and we will respond promptly.

If you have questions, we can be reached by [email](http://www.paloalto.com/uk/contact_us/general_inquiries/).

* * *
